https://fulwoodfmc.net/more-information/data-privacy-notice/

Instagram
RSS Data Privacy NoticeFulwood Free Methodist Church, Fulwood, Preston
Your personal data – what is it?Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data.  Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”). Who are we? The Board of Fulwood Free Methodist Church [the Board] is the data controller (contact details below).  This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.How do we process your personal data?The Board complies with its obligations under the “GDPR” by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.We use your personal data for the following purposes: –To enable us to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public in a particular geographical area as specified in our constitution;To administer membership records;To fundraise and promote the interests of the charity;To manage our employees and volunteers;To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications);To inform you of news, events, activities and services running at, or run by, Fulwood Free Methodist solely or in partnership with other churches & organisations;What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?Explicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aid donations and keep you informed about events.Processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement;Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided: –the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); andthere is no disclosure to a third party without consent. Sharing your personal data.Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church. We will only share your data with third parties outside of the parish with your consent. How long do we keep your personal data[1]?We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the guide “Keep or Bin: Care of Your Parish Records” which is available from the Church of England website [see footnote for link].Specifically, we retain data while it is still current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to 6 years after the calendar year to which they relate; and registers (marriages, funerals) permanently. Your rights and your personal data Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: –The right to request a copy of your personal data which the Board holds about you;The right to request that the Board corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the Board to retain such data;The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any timeThe right to request that the data controller provide the data subject with his/her personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), (where applicable) [Only applies where the processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of a contract with the data subject and in either case the data controller processes the data by automated means].The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable) [Only applies where processing is based on legitimate interests (or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority); direct marketing and processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics]The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office. Further processingIf we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing. Contact DetailsTo exercise all relevant rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the Church Secretary / Administrator at Geoff Tomlinson / Vicky Johns Tel: 01772 861597 office@fulwoodfmc.net .You can contact the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.[1] Details about retention periods can currently be found in the Record Management Guides located on the Church of England website at: – https://www.churchofengland.org/sites/default/files/2017-11/care_of_parish_records_keep_or_bin_-_2009_edition.pdfSpecial Events Unexpected Encounters | Sunday Service 13th December 2020 @ 11:00am
13/12/2020CategoriesCategoriesSelect CategoryBlog   Catching the Wave   Church Life      “Fulwood Scattered” Gathering      “Fulwood Scattered” Update      Corona Virus Updates      Marriage Week 2020   Family   FFMC   Fulwood Free Music   fulwoodfmc.net   Global Partnership   Haiti   Heart Magazine   Inclusion   It’s Friday   Prayer   Printout   Talks Series Information   The Bible in a Year   Weekend ReflectionsEvents   40th Anniversary   All Age August 2020   Annual Conference 2011   Annual Conference 2014   Annual Conference 2015   Annual Conference 2016   Annual Conference 2017   Annual Conference 2018   Conferences   Elevate 2016   FM UK Conference 2013   Inspire 2014   Men’s Breakfast   Rise Tea Party 2015   Toddlers OnlinePodcasts   Gathering      Sunday AM      Sunday PM   Series      …and then what?      “I BELIEVE…”      1 Corinthians      A Rock and Heart Place      Advent 2016      All Age August      August Evenings      Autumn Evenings 2014      Being a Loving Community      Being Men      Bible Blockbusters      Blessings from Ruth      by Invitation      Celebrate His Story      Christmas Journeys      Christmas Unwrapped      CIRCUMSTANCES      Coming to Christ      COMING TO CHRIST (2015)      Dig Deeper 2016      Each One Reach One      Evenings 2010      Faith Foundations      FAITH UNDER PRESSURE      Five Hot Topics      Focus on the Cross      Freedom      FRONTLINE      Go Deeper      God Calling      Going for Gold – Fit for Life      Hark the Herald Angels Sing      Have I got news for you!      Hebrews      I AM      Impact      Inspire and Equip      Invitation to God      Jesus’ Parables Through Middle Eastern Eyes      Journey to Christmas      Larger than Life      Letter to My Younger Self      Life in the Crossfire      Life Stories      Life’s Healing Choices      Live at peace with one another      Living a Great Life      Living for Pure Pleasure      Living the Transformed Life      Love Letters from the Lord      Make Way for the King      Money Matters      One Day | Three Stories      Ordinary Heroes      Parables      Prayer Through Lent      Red Letter Messages      Romans      S.H.A.P.E.D. to Serve      Set Free      Songs for All Seasons      Steve Bell      Strengthening Church      Strengthening Church (Part 2)      Stretching Our Faith      Summer in Rome      Sunday School Stories      Talking Jesus      Ten Commandments      The Church      The Lord’s Prayer Pattern      The Nehemiah Diaries      The Prayer Course      The Preston Questions      The Short Epistles      Things Jesus Never Said      This is Easter      Titus      Transformed by the Holy Spirit      TRANSFORMED LIFE      Unexpected Christmas      Welcome Stranger      What does Jesus say to…?      What I really really want to know is…      What would Jesus say…      When the Devil Knocks      Who am I?      Why we believe in…      Women of the New Testament      Words of the Cross      YOUR KINGDOM COME   Speakers      Alex Sayer      Allan Ellershaw      Andrew Gardner      Andrew Gawne      Andrew Ollerton      Andrew Woof      Andy Barnett      Barbara Clark      Becky Crawford      Ben Woodfield      Bernard Cocker      Beth Sleet      Bishop David Roller      Bishop Matt Thomas      Bishop Nikolai      Bishop Samuel Kayinamura      Bob Hardman      Brian Whaite      Chick Yuill      Chris Drury      Chris Kelsall      Cole Maynard      Cristi Murgu      Cyril Ashton      Daf Meirion-Jones      Dan Cronin      Dan Feeny      Dave Bilsborough      Dave Brown      Dave Carr      Dave Ginns      Dave Harrison      Dave Riley      Dave Scholes      Dave Sewell      David Gibb      David Harvey      David Heart      David Smith      David Wilkinson      Deirdre Brower Latz      Derek Tidball      Des Wadsworth      Diana Jackson      Esther Scholes      Fiona Castle      Gareth Davies      Gareth Earnshaw      Gerard Charles      Gilbert L van Bueren      Graham Chastney      Graham Cutler      Graham Norcross      Greg Downes      Hazel Sewell      Ian Clarkson      Ian Higginbotham      Ian Stackhouse      J. B. Walton      Jason Buckler      Jason Gardner      Joanna Clarkson      John Duckett      John Nuttall      John Sainsbury      John Townley      Johnny Lee      Jonathan Gardner      Julian Henderson      Justyn Towler      Larry Walkemeyer      Lawrence Davie      Linda McGuinness      Lindsay Bruce      Lisa Bell      Mansell Morgan      Marcie Potts      Mark Johnstone      Mark Ritchie      Mark Sleet      Michael Bretton      Mike Faun      Neil Hudson      Nick Cuthbert      Nick Kenworthy      Paul Blackham      Paul Jackson      Peter Read      Phil Talbot      Rachel Gardner      Rebecca Parkinson      Rhiannon Goulding      Richard Scholes      Richard Taylor      Rob Whittaker      Rob WIlliams      Robert Walsh      Ron Farrington      Roy Bourner      Sarah Jones      Sarah McKerney      Sarah Parker      Simon Airey      Simon Gardner      Simon Huggon      Sonya Buckle      Stephen Roberts      Steve Brady      Steve Evans      Steve Fenton      Steve Goss      Steve Karma      Sue Chastney      Sue Kelsall      Sue Marsden      Trevor Crawford      Viv Walker      Will MarsdenPreachersStoriesSubjectsUncategorizedWebsite
Archives Archives Select Month December 2020 November 2020 October 2020 September 2020 August 2020 July 2020 June 2020 May 2020 April 2020 March 2020 February 2020 January 2020 December 2019 November 2019 October 2019 September 2019 August 2019 July 2019 June 2019 May 2019 April 2019 March 2019 February 2019 January 2019 December 2018 November 2018 October 2018 September 2018 August 2018 July 2018 June 2018 May 2018 April 2018 March 2018 February 2018 January 2018 December 2017 November 2017 October 2017 September 2017 August 2017 July 2017 June 2017 May 2017 April 2017 March 2017 February 2017 January 2017 December 2016 November 2016 October 2016 September 2016 August 2016 July 2016 June 2016 May 2016 April 2016 March 2016 February 2016 January 2016 December 2015 November 2015 October 2015 September 2015 August 2015 July 2015 June 2015 May 2015 April 2015 March 2015 February 2015 January 2015 December 2014 November 2014 October 2014 September 2014 August 2014 July 2014 June 2014 May 2014 April 2014 March 2014 February 2014 January 2014 December 2013 November 2013 October 2013 September 2013 August 2013 July 2013 June 2013 May 2013 April 2013 March 2013 February 2013 January 2013 December 2012 November 2012 October 2012 September 2012 August 2012 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 April 2008 February 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006
